Administrators' Annual Reports Collection UA036
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Administrators' Annual Reports Collection
1971 -- 2006
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of the President
UA036
3.9 Linear Feet 6 boxes
2 Digital Object(s) 2 digital objects comprising 46 files.
11.2 Megabytes
Arrangement
This collection is organized in two series: Administrators' annual reports and Additional accessions.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains annual reports of administrators. These include all reports submitted by the school and division deans and vice presidents to the Office of the President. Not all schools, programs or departments submit a report each year. Offices most often represented include: Senior Vice President and Provost; Executive Vice President; Deans of Liberal Arts and Jackson, the College of Engineering, the Graduate School (A&S), Fletcher School, School of Nutrition, School of Dental Medicine, School of Veterinary Medicine, Sackler School; the Directors of the Human Nutrition Research Center, European Center, Summer School and Continuing Education. There are also reports from the Librarian, University Counsel, and other central departments.
Every year, the dean of each school or head of each program or major university division submits an annual report to the president. This report is bound with the other deans' reports and distributed back to the departments that submitted them. This compiled report is sometimes called "Administrators' Annual Reports." Prior to 1971, these reports were bound as appendices to the president's annual report to the Board of Trustees. In 1971 the Administrators Annual Reports were bound together separate from the president's report.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of the President is responsible for regulating and overseeing the general administration of the University. Along with various administrative duties, each year the president prepares an annual report which is delivered to the Board of Trustees. This state of the university report generally includes information about past and present college affairs and policies, as well as future plans and suggestions. The Office of the President was the first, and for a time only, administrative office. Originally, the president performed virtually all administrative duties. Presidents usually were members of the faculty as well. In the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, as administrative functions became more complex, the duties of the president were spread among other administrators. With the professionalization of college and university administration in the mid-twentieth century, specialized administrative offices were created, and faculty no longer performed dual roles of educators and administrators.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Administration and Governance -- Planning, evaluation, policies & procedures
- Administrators' Annual Reports, 1971 -- 2006; UA036.001; 3.65 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s) 2 digital objects comprising 46 files.; 11.2 Megabytes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains annual reports of administrators from 1971 through 2006. These include all reports submitted by the school and division deans and vice presidents to the Office of the President. Not all schools, programs or departments submit a report each year. Offices most often represented include: Senior Vice President and Provost; Executive Vice President; Deans of Liberal Arts and Jackson, the College of Engineering, the Graduate School (A&S), Fletcher School, School of Nutrition, School of Dental Medicine, School of Veterinary Medicine, Sackler School; the Directors of the Human Nutrition Research Center, European Center, Summer School and Continuing Education. There are also reports from the Librarian, University Counsel, and other central departments.
  Every year, the dean of each school or head of each program or major university division submits an annual report to the president. This report is bound with the other deans' reports and distributed back to the departments that submitted them. This compiled report is sometimes called "Administrators' Annual Reports." Prior to 1971, these reports were bound as appendices to the president's annual report to the Board of Trustees. In 1971 the Administrators Annual Reports were bound together separate from the president's report.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: October 30 (1/2), 1971; UA036.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Open for research.
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: October 30 (2/2), 1971; UA036.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Administrators' Reports to the President: October 28 (1/2), 1972; UA036.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Administrators' Reports to the President: October 28 (2/2), 1972; UA036.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Administrators' Reports to the President: November 3 (1/2), 1973; UA036.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Administrators' Reports to the President: November 3 (2/2), 1973; UA036.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: November 2, 1974; UA036.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: November 1 (1/2), 1975; UA036.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: November 1 (2/2), 1975; UA036.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: October 30, 1976; UA036.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: November 4, 1977; UA036.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: October 28, 1978; UA036.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: November 3, 1979; UA036.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President, 1979 -- 1980; UA036.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President (1/2), 1980 -- 1981; UA036.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President (2/2), 1980 -- 1981; UA036.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President, 1981 -- 1982; UA036.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President: July 16, 1982; UA036.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President (2/3), 1982 -- 1983; UA036.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President (3/3), 1982 -- 1983; UA036.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President (1/3), 1983 -- 1984; UA036.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President (2/3), 1983 -- 1984; UA036.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President (3/3), 1983 -- 1984; UA036.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President, 1983 -- 1984; UA036.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President, 1984 -- 1985; UA036.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President, UA036.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Reports to the President, 1980; UA036.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Annual Administrative Report to the President, 1985 -- 1986; UA036.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Annual Administrative Report to the President, 1985 -- 1986; UA036.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Annual Administrative Report to the President, 1985 -- 1986; UA036.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report (Provost), 1984 -- 1985; UA036.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report Department of Physical Education/Athletic/Recreation, 1986 -- 1987; UA036.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report of the Department of Engineering Design, 1986 -- 1987; UA036.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report of the Department of Mechanical Engineering, 1986 -- 1987; UA036.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Annual Administrative Report to the President, November 13, 1987; UA036.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1987; UA036.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1987; UA036.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1987; UA036.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports from Deans, Administrators, etc., 1987 -- 1988; UA036.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports from Deans, Administrators, etc., 1987 -- 1988; UA036.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports from Deans, Administrators, etc., 1987 -- 1988; UA036.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports of the Department of Physiology, 1988; UA036.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports of the Department of Physical Education/Athletic/Recreation, 1988 -- 1989; UA036.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' Annual Reports to the President, 1988 -- 1989; UA036.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' Annual Reports to the President, 1988 -- 1989; UA036.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' Annual Reports to the President, 1988 -- 1989; UA036.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' Annual Reports to the President, part 2, 1988 -- 1989; UA036.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' Annual Reports to the President, part 2, 1988 -- 1989; UA036.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports to the President from Schools of the University, 1989 -- 1990; UA036.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports to the President from Schools of the University, 1989 -- 1990; UA036.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports to the President from Central Administration, 1990; UA036.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports to the President from Central Administration, 1990; UA036.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' Annual Reports, Book 1, 1991; UA036.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' Annual Reports, Book 1, 1991; UA036.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' Annual Reports, Book 1, 1991; UA036.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Administrators' annual reports, book 2, 1991; UA036.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Administrators' annual reports, book 1 (part 1 of 2), 1992; UA036.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Administrators' annual reports, book 1 (part 2 of 2), 1992; UA036.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Administrators' annual reports, book 2, 1992; UA036.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Annual report of the Dean of the Colleges of Liberal Arts and Jackson, 1993; UA036.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1993 -- 1994; UA036.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1994 -- 1995; UA036.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1996 -- 1997; UA036.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Annual reports of the Provost, Deans, and Vice Presidents, 1995 -- 1996; UA036.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports of the Provost, Deans, and Vice Presidents, 1997 -- 1998; UA036.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports of the Provost, Deans, and Vice Presidents, 1998 -- 1999; UA036.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports of the Provost, Deans, and Vice Presidents, 1999 -- 2000; UA036.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports of the Provost, Deans, and Vice Presidents, 2000 -- 2001; UA036.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports of the Provost, Deans, and Vice Presidents, 2001 -- 2002; UA036.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Annual Report of the Provost, Deans, and Vice President (Administrators' Annual Reports), 2002 -- 2003; UA036.001.006 (Box 5)
  - Administrators Annual Reports, 2004 -- 2005; UA036.001.007; 3.5 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 23 files.
    20 years from date of creation.
    CD-R. Two identical copies.
  - Administrators Annual Reports, 2005 -- 2006; UA036.001.008; 7.7 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 23 files.
    CD-R. Two nearly identical copies.
- Additional accessions, UA036.000074
  - Administrators' Annual Reports, 2004 -- 2006; UA036-003 (Box data_value_missing_498791eb98799a80c7fccaa8409ea9a6, Box 1)
    CD's